(indigenous name: Magdapio Falls) is one of the most famous waterfalls in the Philippines. Located in theprovince of Laguna, the falls is one of the major tourist attractions of the region. The three-drop waterfall is reached by a river trip ondugout canoe, known locally as Shooting the rapids, originating from the municipality of Pagsanjan. The falls can also be reached from the top by a short hike from Cavinti. The boat ride has been an attraction since the Spanish Colonial Era with the oldest written account in 1894. The town of Pagsanjan lies at the confluence of two rivers, the Balanac River and the Bumbungan River(also known as the Pagsanjan River).
Officially the City of Vigan (Ilokano: Ciudad ti Bigan; Tagalog: Lungsod ng Vigan) is a fourth class city and capital of theprovince of Ilocos Sur in the Philippines. The city is located on the western coast of the large island of Luzon, facing the South China Sea. According to the 2010 Philippines census, it has a population of 49,747 people.
The Banaue Rice Terraces (Filipino: Hagdan-hagdang Palayan ng Banawe) are 2,000-year-old terraces that were carved into the mountains of Ifugao in the Philippines by ancestors of the indigenous people. The Rice Terraces are commonly referred to as the "Eighth Wonder of the World".
is a wind farm in Bangui, Ilocos Norte, Philippines. The wind farm uses 20 units of 70-metre (230 ft) high VestasV82 1.65 MW wind turbines, arranged on a single row stretching along a nine-kilometer shoreline off Bangui Bay, facing the West Philippine Sea.
The Hundred Islands National Park (Pangasinan: Kapulo-puloan or Taytay-Bakes) is a national park in the Philippines. Theprotected area is located in the city of Alaminos, in the province of Pangasinan in northern Philippines. The islands, totaling 124 at low tide and 123 at high tide, are scattered in Lingayen Gulf covering an area of 16.76 square kilometres (6.47 sq mi). Only three of them have been developed for tourism: Governor Island, Quezon Island, and Children's Island.
Lake Caliraya is a man-made lake situated in the municipalities of Lumban, Cavinti, and Kalayaan in Laguna province, Philippines. Created in 1939, the lake has developed as a popular spot for water sports and outdoor recreation including fishing. Surrounding the lake are a number of resorts catering to tourists and vacation homes abound because of the beautiful scenery and favorable climate.
is an active volcano in the province of Albay, on the island of Luzon in the Philippines. Renowned as the "perfect cone" because of its almost symmetricconical shape, the mountain and its surrounding landscape was declared a national park on July 20, 1938, the first in the country. It was reclassified a Natural Park and renamed Mayon Volcano Natural Park in the year 2000.
is the 3rd highest mountain in the Philippines . It is Luzon's highest peak at 2,922 meters above sea level. The borders between the provinces of Benguet, Ifugao, and Nueva Vizcaya meet at the mountain's peak. It is the third highest mountain in the Philippines, next to Mount Apo and Mount Dulang-dulang. Mount Pulag is famous for its majestic "sea of clouds" and the view of the Milky Way Galaxy at dawn, which has attracted many tourists who wish to see the "other-worldly" scenery.
Taal Lake is a freshwater lake in the province of Batangas, on the island of Luzon in the Philippines. The lake fills Taal Caldera, a large volcanic caldera formed by very large eruptions between 500,000 and 100,000 years ago. It is the country's third largest lake after Laguna de Bay and Lake Lanao. Volcano Island, the location of Taal Volcano's historical eruptions and responsible for the lake's sulfuric content, lies near the center of the lake.
Villa Escudero  is 800 hectares (2,000 acres) of working coconut plantation and hacienda located 10 kilometres (6.2 mi) south of the city of San Pablo, Laguna province on the border with Quezon province in the Philippines. Since 1981, the plantation has opened its doors as a resort offering village tours, museum tour, food and accommodations. It has developed a worldwide reputation as a focal point to experience Philippine culture and history in a beautiful rural setting
is a beautiful lake surrounded by forest. This one of the attractions in Bulusan Volcano Natural Park. Kayaking is the most suggested activity in the lake where you will enjoy great views. Bulusan Lake which is also called as the Switzerland of the Orient can be found in Sorsogon, Luzon, Philippines.
is a calm and clean where you can enjoy with your family some lunch in the center of the lake riding a raft with a roof. This is one of the reasons why Lake Pandin starts to carve its name in the list of tourist spots in Luzon. Lake Pandin is situated in San Pablo, Laguna, Luzon, Philippines.
is also known as Boracay of the North. It is a beautiful white sand beach with clear blue waters. This beach is good for swimming, kayaking and chilling. There are many trees on the shore so you can rest under them. Anguib Beach is located in Santa Ana, Cagayan, Luzon, Philippines.
also called as Mahabang Buhangin (Long Stretch Beach) which is famous for it's powdery white sand beach and clear blue waters. This is a really long stretch beach that gives beautiful scenery. This beach can be described as Boracay Beach 10 years ago. Calaguas Beach is located in Calaguas, Camarines Norte, Luzon, Philippines.
also known as Luneta National Park or simply Luneta, is a historical urban park in the Philippines. Located along Roxas Boulevard, Manila, adjacent to the old walled city of Intramuros, it is one of the largest urban parks in Asia. It has been a favorite leisure spot, and is frequented on Sundays and national holidays. Rizal Park is one of the major tourist attractions of Manila.
is an overlook park on the northeastern outskirts of Baguio in the Philippines.Located on a land promontory 4 km from downtown Baguio, the park overlooks the mining town of Itogon, particularly the abandoned gold1 and copper mines of the Benguet Corporation, and offers a glimpse of theAmburayan Valley. 
is an active volcano on Luzon in the Philippines. The three-peaked volcano complex is located between the provinces of Laguna and Quezon and is the tallest mountain in the CALABARZON region dominating the landscape for miles around. The mountain is considered by many as a "Holy mountain" and is popular among pilgrims along with mountain climbers. It is located in a protected area known as Mounts Banahaw–San Cristobal Protected Landscapecovering 10,901 hectares (26,940 acres) of land.
is the longest mountain range in the Philippines. Running in the north-south direction from the provinces of Cagayan to the north and Quezon to the south, the mountains form the eastern backbone of Luzon Island, the largest island of the archipelago. It is bordered by the Pacific Ocean to the east. The Pacific coast of Luzon along the Sierra Madre is less developed as the lofty and continuous mountains forms a bold and an almost inaccessible shore, exposed to the full force of the northeast monsoon and the waves of the Pacific Ocean.1 Some of communities east of the mountain range and along the coast are so remote they are still only accessible by plane or by boat.
is a potentially active stratovolcano located in the province of Camarines Sur, Philippines, on the island of Luzon. It has an elevation of 2,000 metres above mean sea level. The peak of the mountain marks the point where the borders of five municipalities and one city meet (listed in clockwise direction, starting north): Goa, Tigaon, Ocampo, Pili, Naga City, and Calabanga. Mount Isarog was where local troops of the Philippine Army and Constabulary units and Bicolano guerrillas hid during the Japanese Period. In the 1970s, with the leadership of Romulo Jallores and his brother, they established the New People's Army in the Bicol region at the foot of this mountain. 
is a famous attraction along Kennon Road, a major highway in Luzon, Philippines that leads to the city of Baguio. Located in Camp 6, the Lion's Head measures 40 ft (12 m) in height.It was conceptualized by the Lions Club members of Baguio City, during the term of Luis Lardizabal as mayor of Baguio City from 1969 to 1970 and as the club's president, to become the club's symbol or imprint in the area. Prior to the artistic sculpting, the limestone was prepared by a group of engineers and miners, then the "actual artistic carving of the façade" was rendered by Reynaldo Lopez Nanyac, an Ifugao artist and woodcarver from the Cordillera Administrative Region. The construction project began in 1968 but was interrupted. The project was continued in 1971 by another Lions Club president, Robert Webber,and was unveiled in 1972.
Mount Macolod (also called Mount Makulot or Mount Maculot) is a mountain located in the town of Cuenca in Batangas province, in the Philippines. This mountain is popular among mountain climbers and campers; it is the major tourist attraction of the municipality. The mountain is about 947 m (3,107 ft) tall and is also located adjacent to Taal Lake. Mount Makulot and its 700-metre (2,300 ft) high volcanic rock wall called The Rockies, is said to be part of Taal Caldera's crater rim.
The Taal Basilica canonically known as the Minor Basilica of Saint Martin of Tours (Filipino: Basilika ni San Martin ng Tours;Spanish: Basílica Menor de San Martín de Tours) is a Minor Basilica in the town of Taal, Batangas in the Philippines, within theArchdiocese of Lipa. It is considered to be the largest church in the Philippines and in Asia, standing 88.6 metres (291 ft) long and 48 metres (157 ft) wide. St. Martin of Tours is the patron saint of Taal, whose fiesta is celebrated every November 11.
Isla ng Corregidor is an island located at the entrance of Manila Bay in southwestern part of Luzon Island in the Philippines. Due to this location, Corregidor was fortified with several coastal artillery and ammunition magazines to defend the entrance of Manila Bay and the city of Manila from attacks by enemy warships in the event of war. Located 48 kilometres (30 mi) inland, Manila has been the largest city and the most important seaport in the Philippines for centuries, from the colonial rule of Spain, Japan and the United States, to the establishment of the Republic of the Philippines in 1946.
Mount Samat is a historic mountain in the town of Pilár, Province of Bataan, in the Republic of the Philippines. Located near its summit is the Mount Samat National Shrine, a nationalshrine dedicated to the fallen Filipino and American fallen during World War II.
The Aguinaldo Shrine is the national shrine located in Kawit, Cavite in the Republic of the Philippines, where the independence of the Philippines from Spain was declared on June 12, 1898.4 To commemorate the event, now known as Araw ng Kalayaan or Independence Day, a national holiday, the Philippine flag is raised here by top government officials on June 12 each year. The house is now a museum.
Subic Bay is a bay on the west coast of the island of Luzon in the Philippines, about 100 kilometres (62 mi) northwest of Manila Bay. An extension of the South China Sea, its shores were formerly the site of a majorUnited States Navy facility named U.S. Naval Base Subic Bay, which is now the location of an industrial and commercial area known as the Subic Bay Freeport Zone under the Subic Bay Metropolitan Authority.The bay was long recognized for its deep and protected waters, but development was slow due to lack of level terrain around the bay.
Magat Dam is a large rock-fill dam in the island of Luzon in the Philippines. The dam is on the Magat River, a major tributary of Cagayan River. Construction of the dam started in 1975 and was completed in 1982. Magat Dam is one of the largest dams in the Philippines. It is a multi-purpose dam which is used primarily for irrigating about 85,000 hectares (210,000 acres) of agricultural lands,1 flood control, and power generation through the Magat Hydroelectric Power Plant.
The Chico River (Spanish: Rio Chico de Cagayan) is a river system in the Philippines in the island of Luzon, encompassing the regions of Cordillera and Cagayan Valley.The most extensive river in the Cordillera region, it covers the provinces of Mountain Province, Kalinga andCagayan. It is one of the major tributaries of the Cagayan River.It is referred to as a "river of life" for the Kalinga people who live on its banks, and is well known among development workers because of the Chico River Dam Project, an electric power generation project which local residents resisted for three decades before it was finally shelved in the 1980s - a landmark case study concerning ancestral domain issues in the Philippines.
Hidden Valley Springs is a hot springs resort located in Calauan, Laguna, Philippines. The valley nestles at the foot of Mt. Makiling, an extinct volcano associated with local myths, and the resort was said to be created in the aftermath of a volcanic eruption from the said mountain. A number of springs fill pools flowing with hot, cold and soda water, and they lace a forest of huge fruit trees (some of which have been around for centuries), tropical shrubs and flowering plants. A concrete path connects the pools and leads to the jungle's interior, where a waterfall has cut a gorge down the mountainside (the aforementioned waterfall known popularly as the Hidden Falls, was used as the backdrop for the Miss Universe contest when it was held in Manila). The resort is owned by the Roxas family, whose patriarch Don Eugenio Roxas oversaw the 1.1 square kilometre property as the family estate until they opened it to the tourist public in the early 1970's.
Mount Makiling, or Mount Maquiling, is a dormant volcano in Laguna province on the island of Luzon,Philippines. The mountain rises to an elevation of 1,090 m (3,580 ft) above mean sea level and is the highest feature of the Laguna Volcanic Field. The volcano has no recorded historic eruption but volcanism is still evident through geothermal features like mud spring and hot springs. South of the mountain is the Makiling-Banahaw Geothermal Plant. The Philippine Institute of Volcanology and Seismology (PHIVOLCS) classify the volcano as potentially active.
Manila Bay is a natural harbour which serves the Port of Manila (on Luzon), in the Philippines. Strategically located around the capital city of the Philippines, Manila Bay facilitated commerce and trade between the Philippines and its neighbouring countries, becoming the gateway for socio-economic development even prior to Spanish occupation.
The Minor Basilica and Metropolitan Cathedral of the Immaculate Conception (Filipino: Kalakhang Katedral Basílika ng Maynilà; Spanish: Catedral Basílica Metropolitana de Manila), informally known as Manila Cathedral, is a Roman Catholic basilica located in Manila, Philippines, dedicated to the Blessed Virgin Mary as Our Lady of the Immaculate Conception, the Principal Patroness of the Philippines. The cathedral serves as the see of the Archbishop of Manila.
Fort Santiago (Spanish: Fuerte de Santiago Tagalog: Moog ng Santiago) is a citadel first built by Spanish conquistador, Miguel López de Legazpi for the new established city of Manila in the Philippines. The defense fortress is part of the structures of the walled city of Manila referred to as Intramuros ("within the walls"). The fort is one of the most important historical sites in Manila. Several lives were lost in its prisons during theSpanish Colonial Period and World War II. José Rizal, the Philippine national hero, was imprisoned here before his execution in 1896. The Rizal Shrine museum displays memorabilia of the hero in their collection and the fort features, embedded onto the ground in bronze, his footsteps representing his final walk from his cell to the location of the actual execution.
Mount Malindig (also known as Mount Malindik and Mount Marlangga) is a large potentially activestratovolcano on the island of Marinduque in the Philippines. The name Marinduque itself may have been derived from "Marindik" or "Malindik". The tale told by the people of Buenavista, the town that sits at the foot of Malindig, is that during the Spanish times, a Spanish soldier got lost. He came upon a girl sitting down sorting rice. He asked her what the name of this place was. She replied in Tagalog "matindig" (translation: "Let me stand up") so she could get a better view of the area. The Spaniard mistook the girl and thought the mountain was called "Matindig", and unable to ennunciate Tagalog, he called it "Malindig. 
The Bathala Caves, located at Santa Cruz, Marinduque, is a complex network of seven caves however only four of which have so far been explored. One of the biggest is called "Simbahan." "Kay Coke" cave, on the other hand, is occasionally guarded by pythons. The third cave has an underground river and the fourth one houses human bones believed to be the remains of World War II soldiers.
Mount Halcon or Monte Halcón is a mountain located in the island of Mindoro in the Philippines. Its height of 2,586 m (8,482 ft) makes it the 18th highest peak in the Philippines. Its slopes have earned it the title to be the most difficult mountain to climb in the country.
Puerto Galera is the north-westernmost municipality in the province of Oriental Mindoro, Philippines. It is located at the south-western end of the Isla Verde Passage, about 130 kilometers (81 mi) south of Manila.
Mount Arayat is an extinct stratovolcano on Luzon Island, Philippines, rising to a height of 1,026 metres (3,366 ft) There is no recorded eruption of the volcano, and its last activity probably dates to the Holoceneera. The southern half of the mountain lies within the municipality of Arayat, Pampanga, while the north half and the mountain summit lies within Magalang.
The Santa Catalina de Alejandria Church, also refereed to as the Arayat Church, is Renaissance-style church located at Arayat, Pampanga, Philippines. Since its initial construction during the late 1700s, it has been subjected to major alterations and changes such as addition of decorative ornaments and reliefs and re-painting works.
The St. James the Apostle Parish Church (Spanish: Iglesia Parroquial de Santiago Apóstol) commonly known as Betis Church is a Baroque church located in the Betis, Guagua in Pampanga, Philippines under theRoman Catholic Archdiocese of San Fernando. The church was established in 1607 and dedicated to Saint James, the Apostle. It was declared a National Cultural Treasure by the National Museum and the National Commission for Culture and the Arts. 
Hinulugang Taktak is a waterfall in the Philippines found in the province of Rizal on Luzon island. The waterfall area has been designated as a National Park by the Department of Environment and Natural Resources and is one of the two most popular tourist spots in Antipolo, Rizal's capital, the other being the Antipolo Cathedral. In 1990, the waterfall has also been proclaimed as a National Historical Shrine under Republic Act No. 6964. 
Hacienda Luisita is a sugar plantation located in the province of Tarlac, Philippines, owned by Martin Lorenzo and the Cojuangco family, which includesCorazón C. Aquino and Benigno S. Aquino III, the eleventh and fifteenth Presidents, respectively. The hacienda spans various municipalities in the province, including the capital Tarlac City.The estate at 6,453-hectares is as large as Makati City and Pasig City combined.
Callao Cave is one of the limestone caves located in the municipality of Peñablanca, Cagayan province, in thePhilippines. The seven-chamber show cave is one of 300 caves that dot the area and the best known natural tourist attractions of the province. The town is named as Peñablanca (Spanish for white rocks) for the presence of white limestone rocks in the area. Callao Cave is located in the Barangays of Magdalo and Quibal in Peñablanca about 24 km (15 mi) northeast of Tuguegarao City, the capital of the Province of Cagayan.
The Cagayan River, also known as the Rio Grande de Cagayan, is the longest and largest river in thePhilippine Archipelago. It is located in the Cagayan Valley region in northeastern part of Luzon Island and traverses the provinces of Nueva Vizcaya, Quirino, Isabela and Cagayan.
The Malagonlong Bridge (also Puente de Malagonlong) is a five-span 445 ft (136 m) long stone arch bridge built during the Spanish colonial period in Tayabas, Quezon, Philippines. The bridge is known as one of the oldest bridges as well as the longest bridge made during the Spanish era. It was declared a National Cultural Treasure under the Historic Bridges of Tayabas on August 12, 2011. 
The Minor Basilica of Saint Michael the Archangel , (Tagalog: Basilika Menor ni San Miguel Arkangel;Spanish: Basílica Menor de San Miguel Arcángel) commonly known as the Tayabas Basilica, is a Roman Catholic basilica located in Tayabas, Quezon, Philippines under the Roman Catholic Diocese of Lucena. Its titular is Saint Michael the Archangel, whose feast is celebrated annually on September 29.
Burnham Park is a 32.84 hectare urban park located at the heart of the Baguio, in the Philippines. It was named after the American architect and urban planner, Daniel Hudson Burnham who laid the plans for the city. Several stretch of roads around the park lead to Camp John Hay, a former recreational base of the United States Armed Forces in the Philippines.
Kennon Road (formerly the Benguet Road and also known as the Rosario–Baguio Road) is aroadway in Benguet province in the Philippines connecting the mountain city of Baguio to the lowland towns of Rosario and Pugo in La Union province. The project was begun in 1903 and opened for travel on January 29, 1905. It was originally called the Benguet Road and later renamed in honor of its builder, Col.Lyman Walter Vere Kennon of the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers. For travelers coming from Manila or the provinces in the central plains of Luzon, it is the shortest route to Baguio. 
The Mansion House (also known as the The Mansion) is the official summer residence of the President of the Philippines. The mansion is located in the summer capital of the country, Baguio, situated around 5,000 feet (1,500 m) asl in the Cordillera Central Range of northern Luzon.
Our Lady of the Atonement Cathedral, better known as Baguio Cathedral, is a Roman Catholic cathedrallocated at Cathedral Loop adjacent to Session Road in Baguio, the Philippines, and is the see of the Roman Catholic Diocese of Baguio. Dedicated to the Blessed Virgin Mary under the title of Our Lady of Atonement, its distinctive pink exterior, twin spires and stained glass windows make it a popular tourist attraction in Baguio. It served as an evacuation centre under the Japanese Occupation during Second World War.